Guide to the Walter Stainton papers, 1914-1983
Stainton, Walter papers, 1914-1983
- Series IX. W. H. Stainton Personal and Professional Documents
  - Student Papers and Research
    - Bibliography for Andre Antoine (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - Otto Brahm Bibliography (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - Notes and Bibliography About Appia (Box 12, Folder 23)
    - Paper on Jacques Copeau by Caroline Mulford (Box 12, Folder 24)
    - Notes on Jacques Copeau (Box 12, Folder 25)
    - Notes, Bibliography, and Paper on Gordon Craig (Box 12, Folder 26)
    - Assorted Student Papers on Gordon Craig (Box 12, Folder 27)
    - David Belasco: Notes and Bibliography (Box 12, Folder 28)
    - Jacques Copeau and the Vieux Colombrier Bibliography (Box 12, Folder 29)
  - Scheduling and Faculty Related Documents
    - "Report Upon Inspection of #4 S.M.A. Toronto by K.G. Krech and W.H. Stainton, 1918, April 1918 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Public Health Section Bus., Improvisation France, 1945, February 1945 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - "Minutes of the Meeting of the Faculty Committee on Scheduling," 1949, January 20, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - A.E.T.A. Technical Production Section Meeting, South American Room, Hotel Statler, Washington D.C., 1948, December 30, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Interview with Professor Winans, May 23, 1952, May 23, 1952 (Box 8, Folder 50)
    - "A Manual of Play Production," by A.M. Drummond (Box 8, Folder 57)
    - Photo of Cornell Faculty, Including Stainton, Spring 1962, Spring 1962 (Box 9, Folder 54)
    - Personal Date Books, 1965-1981, 1965-1981 (Box 11)
    - University Faculty Minutes and Papers Concerning Death of Professor John Sanford Shearer, 1922, June 14, 1922 (Box 11, Folder 49)
    - Articles and Correspondence About William Strunk Jr., 1936-1957, 1936-1957; Strunk was Cornell Alumni 1896 and a professor at the university. These documents including articles by E.B. White and details of "Romeo and Juliet" starring Norma Shearer, Leslie Howard, John Barrymore, and Basil Rathbone. (Box 12, Folder 36)
  - Graduate Students
    - Correspondence and Thesis Materials Concerning Virginia P. Rogers, 1940-1942, 1940-1942 (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Documents Concerning Graduate Student John W. Young, 1946-1948, 1946-1948 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Documents Concerning Graduate Student Elizabeth Rodewald, 1948-1949, 1948-49 (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Documents Concerning Graduate Student Frederick J. Titcomb, 1948-1949, 1948-1949 (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - Correspondence Between A.M. Drummond, Stainton, and John A. Walker, 1949-1950, 1949-1950; Walker is a PhD student looking for a position during his studies. (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - Correspondence, Papers, and Examinations Concerning Graduate Student Olla Rickett, 1949-1955, 1949-1955 (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - Letters and Documents Concerning Olla Rickett's Thesis, 1957-1958, 1957-1958 (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - Correspondence, Papers, and Examinations Concerning Graduate Student Olla Rickett, 1949-1955, 1949-1955 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Assorted Notes
    - Notes about Film
      - Personal Notes on History of Ithaca's Film Industry (1910s), 1940s-1960s (Box 3, Folder 16)
      - Personal Notes on History of Ithaca's Film Industry (1910s), 1940s-1980s (Box 3, Folder 17)
      - Notes for "A 60-Year Calendar of Motion Pictures" (Box 7, Folder 106)
      - List of Film Titles Available from Teaching Film Custodians, Inc, 1958, July 1958 (Box 10, Folder 17)
      - Papers on Upcoming Movie Information Service, March-April 1960, March-April 1960 (Box 10, Folder 18)
      - Papers from the Society for Film History Research, 1961-1966, 1961-1966 (Box 10, Folder 19)
      - Assorted Notes on Charlie Chaplin (Box 10, Folder 21)
      - Assorted Articles and Notes on Animation (Box 10, Folder 22)
      - Assorted Articles and Papers Concerning Film Censorship (Box 10, Folder 23)
      - Assorted Notes and Pamphlets on the Early History of Film (Box 10, Folder 24)
      - Notes on Evaluating Films (Box 10, Folder 25)
      - Notes on Editing (Box 10, Folder 26)
      - Notes and Criticism on D.W. Griffith's "The Birth of a Nation" (Box 10, Folder 27)
      - Notes and Publications on Propaganda in Films (Box 10, Folder 28)
      - Notes and Documents Concerning Experimental Films (Box 10, Folder 29)
      - Assorted Documents and Notes Concerning the Career of Director John Ford (Box 10, Folder 30)
      - A Glossary of Film Terms (Box 10, Folder 32)
      - Papers on Turning Novels into Films (Box 10, Folder 103)
      - Assorted Papers Concerning Sound in Film (Box 10, Folder 104)
      - "The Tax Rate VS the Death Rate," and Assorted Notes, November 26, 1951, November 26, 1951 (Box 13, Folder 16)
      - Descriptions of Various Films (Box 13, Folder 17)
      - Notes on Documentaries (Box 13, Folder 18)
      - Miscellaneous Index Cards and Paraphernalia (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - Notes about Theatre
      - Various Lists of Performed or Suggested Plays and Films, 1926-1950, 1926-1950 (Box 1, Folder 36)
      - Notes on Dramatic Art and School Theatres (Box 3, Folder 97)
      - Collection of Theatre Related Personal Note Cards (Box 3, Folder 98)
      - Notes from Presentations on Theatre Photography and Related Correspondence, September 1940-November 1941 (Box 7, Folder 16)
      - Suggestions for Reviewing Books and Plays, from Players Magazine (Box 7, Folder 39)
      - List of Heerman's Prize plays, with Report and Comments, 1940-1946, 1940-1946 (Box 7, Folder 97)
      - Assorted Theatre and Film Articles and Notes (Box 7, Folder 101)
      - Assorted Notes and Articles on Stage Photography (Box 7, Folder 103)
      - Misc. Lists of Short/Long Plays (Box 7, Folder 104)
      - Guidelines for Coaches of Plays, 1920s, 1920s (Box 8, Folder 27)
      - Cornell Daily Sun Article About Improved Theatre Lighting, 1948, October 26, 1948; Features Fred Stephan '51 in photos. (Box 8, Folder 29)
      - Notices About Cornell Theatre Pertaining to A.M. Drummond, 1949-1952, 1949-1952 (Box 8, Folder 30)
      - Assorted Theatre Notes (Box 10, Folder 20)
      - Assorted Theatre Related Documents (Box 10, Folder 33)
      - Notes for Unidentified Play Concerning Egypt (Box 10, Folder 34)
      - Articles and Notes on Stage Design (Box 10, Folder 35)
      - Assorted Theatre Notes Course and Theatre Documents (Box 10, Folder 37)
      - Various Articles and Notes on Theatre (Box 10, Folder 38)
      - Note Cards with Theatre Information (Box 10, Folder 50)
      - Assorted Theatre Statistics and Reading Lists (Box 10, Folder 102)
      - Various Theatre Reading Lists and Articles (Box 10, Folder 105)
      - Papers from an Unidentified Play (Box 10, Folder 106)
      - Various Papers About Actors and Play Production (Box 10, Folder 107)
      - Assorted Theatre and Acting Notes (Box 12, Folder 77)
    - Assorted Personal Notes (Box 3, Folder 99)
    - "Observations of the Total Solar Eclipse of January 25, 1926 Made by Electric Companies Affiliated with the Consolidated Gas Company of New York (Box 5, Folder 101)
    - Assorted Notes for Presentation at Ann Arbor Conference, 1950, 1950 (Box 7, Folder 98)
    - 4th Festival of Contemporary Arts: Notes on Presentation, 1950, April 1950 (Box 7, Folder 99)
    - Notes and Card from ΘΑΦ Formal Initiation and Banquet, 1951, April 17, 1951 (Box 7, Folder 100)
    - Misc. Notes, Majority Handwritten (Box 7, Folder 102)
    - "Color Music" Note Cards (Box 7, Folder 105)
    - CU Department of Public Speaking and Drama Newsletter, 1941-1950, 1941-1950 (Box 8, Folder 28)
    - Photos of Cornell Faculty, May 1952, May 1952; Includes President Malotte (Box 8, Folder 31)
    - Papers from Cornell University United Fund, 1965-1973, 1965-1973 (Box 9, Folder 55)
    - Papers from Cornell University United Fund, 1965-1973, 1934-1935 (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Assorted Notes and Reports on Propaganda (Box 10, Folder 31)
    - Articles and Notes About Georges Melies (Box 10, Folder 36)
    - Notes on Propaganda (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - Assorted Voting Advertisements as Propaganda (Box 10, Folder 101)
    - Papers on Professor Erwin Panofsky of Princeton (Box 10, Folder 108)
    - Papers on "The Ghost Goes West" and Rene Clair (Box 10, Folder 109)
    - Assorted Papers Related to Show Boats (Box 10, Folder 110)
    - Notes on William Fricse-Green, 1855-1921, 1855-1921 (Box 11, Folder 29)
    - Notes on Charles Francis Jenkins, 1869-1934, 1869-1934 (Box 11, Folder 30)
    - Notes on Exhibits in Science Museum, South Kensington (Box 11, Folder 31)
    - Notes Concerning A. M. Demeny (Box 11, Folder 32)
    - Notes on Alexander Black (Box 11, Folder 33)
    - M.P. General (Box 11, Folder 34)
    - Notes on George Eastman (Box 11, Folder 35)
    - Assorted Notes on Carpenter Library (Box 11, Folder 36)
    - Assorted Notes on Dioramas (Box 11, Folder 37)
    - Notes on Patents (Box 11, Folder 38)
    - Notes Concerning Louis Aime Augustin Le Prince (Box 11, Folder 39)
    - Note Cards of Panoramas from New York Public Library (Box 11, Folder 40)
    - Notes on Panoramas (Box 11, Folder 41)
    - Notes and Articles on the Panorama of Gettysburg in Boston (Box 11, Folder 42)
    - Notes on Eugene A. Lauste (Box 11, Folder 43)
    - Assorted Notes on the History of New York (Box 11, Folder 44)
    - Notes About Etienne Jules Marey (Box 11, Folder 45)
    - Notes on the Lumiere Brothers from France (Box 11, Folder 46)
    - Notes on Loops (Box 11, Folder 47)
    - Miscellaneous Notes (Box 11, Folder 48)
    - Patent #61976, Louis Ducos du Hauron, 1864-1864, 1864-1864 (Box 11, Folder 57)
    - Ducos du Hauron Patient of 1896 - Translation, 1896 (Box 11, Folder 58)
    - "Louis Ducos du Hauron" by Georges Patonnlee, 1914, A1914 (Box 11, Folder 59)
    - Assorted Papers Relating to the Ducos du Hauron Family (Box 11, Folder 60)
    - Assorted Notes and Papers, mid-1960s, Mid-1960s (Box 13, Folder 60)
    - Assorted Professional Documents, 1940s, 1940s (Box 13, Folder 61)
  - Assorted Correspondence
    - Assorted Correspondence and Papers, 1960-1964, 1960-1964 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Assorted Notes and Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Assorted Notes and Paperwork (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Letters of Correspondence, February 1939-August 1953, Many of these letters are between Stainton and J. H. North (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Letters Between Stainton and R.M. Schmitz, April-May 1940, April-May 1940 (Box 3, Folder 60)
    - Correspondence about Auditorium of Oswego State Normal School, 1941, 1941 (Box 5, Folder 91)
    - Letters to Stainton from Jim Sheehey of Hotel State College, 1938 (Box 5, Folder 92)
    - Letters to Stainton from Jim Sheehey of Hotel State College, 1938, 1938 (Box 5, Folder 93)
    - Letter from Stainton to Keeneth Maigowan, University of California, December 11, 1951, December 11, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 93)
    - Correspondence Between Stainton and Magaziner and Eberhardt Architects, Augusut 1953, August 1952 (Box 5, Folder 94)
    - Correspondence Between Stainton and Museum of Modern Art Library Concerning Rentals, 1935-1936, 1935-1936 (Box 7, Folder 75)
    - Correspondence Between Stainton and Museum of Modern Art Library Concerning Rentals, 1936-1937, 1936-1937 (Box 7, Folder 76)
    - Correspondence Between Stainton and Museum of Modern Art Library Concerning Rentals, 1937-1938, 1937-1938 (Box 7, Folder 77)
    - Notes, Articles and Correspondence Concerning Research for "Color Music," Late 1930s, Late 1930s (Box 7, Folder 78)
    - Correspondence Concerning Citation Permission for "Color Music," June 1942, June 1942 (Box 7, Folder 79)
    - Correspondence with Eastman Kodak Company about Theatre Photography, 1937-1941, 1937-1941 (Box 7, Folder 80)
    - Assorted Correspondence Concerning Stage Photography, 1937-1941, 1937-1941 (Box 7, Folder 81)
    - Documents and Correspondence Concerning Federal Theatre Project, 1938, 1938 (Box 7, Folder 82)
    - Correspondence Between Stainton and Museum of Modern Art, 1939-1940, 1939-1940; Focus between Stainton and Iris Barry (founder of the museum's Film Department/Curator of the museum) about film lecture. (Box 7, Folder 83)
    - Correspondence Conerning Syracuse Museum of Fine Arts Theatre Reconstruction, 1940, June 14-17,1940 (Box 7, Folder 84)
    - Assorted Correspondence, 1941-1952, 1941-1952 (Box 7, Folder 85)
    - Correspondnece Between Stainton and Elmira Little Theatre, 1946-1953, 1946-1953 (Box 7, Folder 86)
    - Letter to Ray Howes About Theatre Availability, 1947, October 6, 1947 (Box 7, Folder 87)
    - Letters to Foster Coffin About Willard Straight Theatre, 1947-1948, 1947-1948 (Box 7, Folder 88)
    - Letters Concerning Production of "Her Heart Was Richer Than Gold," 1948, 1948 (Box 7, Folder 89)
    - Correspondence Concerning Ann Arbor Conference,1951, 1950 (Box 7, Folder 90)
    - Various Notes, Articles, and Correspondence Concerning Theatre Construction, 1950-1951 (Box 7, Folder 91)
    - Drafts and Correspondence Concerning "Let's Look at Lighting" for Players Magazine, 1951, 1951 (Box 7, Folder 92)
    - Correspondence and Commentary on "Low-Budget Stage Lighting" By John A. Walter for Cincinnati Convention, 1952, December 1952 (Box 7, Folder 93)
    - Correspondence Between Stainton and Players Magazine About "Stage Lighting" Article, 1952-1953, 1952-1953 (Box 7, Folder 94)
    - Letter from American Education Theatre Association Concerning "Stage Lighting," 1953, April 25, 1953 (Box 7, Folder 95)
    - A.M. Drummond Telegrams and Correspondence, 1930-1948, 1930-1948 (Box 8, Folder 42)
    - Correspondence Between Stainton, A.M. Drummond, and Philip Freund, May-August 1946, May-August 1946 (Box 8, Folder 43)
    - Correspondnece With Surrey Community Players, 1951-1952, 1951-1952 (Box 8, Folder 44)
    - Assorted Correspondence (Box 8, Folder 45)
    - Correspondence Between Ithaca Schools and Stainton Asking for Theatre Advice, 1956-1966, 1956-1966 (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Assorted Correspondence, 1936-1962, 1936-1962 (Box 10, Folder 56)
    - Correspondence Between Stainton and Dr. B.W. Hewitt over Switchboards, 1934-1935, 1934-1935 (Box 11, Folder 56)
    - Correspondence with "Theatre Arts Monthly," May 1936-December 1939, May 1936-December 1939 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence with "Theatre Arts Monthly," January 1940-July 1943, January 1940-July 1943 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Assorted Correspondence, Mainly on Acquiring Films, 1948-1965, 1948-1965 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence with Henry Hart, 1950-1960, 1950-1960 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Assorted Correspondence, Mainly Focused on Articles and Movie-Going, 1962-1963, 1962-1963 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence About Theatre Collections, 1963, 1963 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Assorted Correspondence (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Assorted Correspondence with Friends (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence with American Museum of Photograph. July-September 1965, July-September 1965 (Box 13, Folder 59)
    - Assorted Correspondence, 1937-1966, 1937-1966 (Box 15, Folder 19)
    - Assorted Correspondence, 1938-1964, 1938-1964 (Box 15, Folder 19)
    - Correspondence About National Board of Review of Motion Pictures, March 1964, March 1964 (Box 15, Folder 36)
  - Society for Cinema Studies, The Society for Cinema Studies was originally called the Society of Cinematologists and is known today as The Society for Cinema and Media Studies. Several of these documents refer to when the Society was under its original name, but these have been listed under the Society for Cinema Studies for consistency and to prevent confusion.
    - Treasury Documents for the Society for Cinema Studies (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Curriculum Vitae for Theatre Professionals (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Assorted Documents from the Society for Cinema Studies (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Constitution of the Society for Cinema Studies, with Various Edits (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence Concerning Society for Cinema Studies, 1960-1971, 1960-1971 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Documents Concerning Society for Cinema Studies Conferences, 1960-1985, 1960-1985 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Meeting Minutes from The Society for Cinema Studies, 1961-1975, 1961-1975 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Society for Cinema Studies Membership, 1963-1979, 1963-1979 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Society for Cinema Studies Newsletter, 1965-1981, 1965-1981 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence Concerning Society for Cinema Studies, 1972-1984, 1972-1984 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Assorted Documents Concerning Film and Society for Cinema Studies (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - Article from Society of Cinematologists, 1960, March 16, 1960 (Box 11, Folder 62)
  - Miscellaneous
    - The National Board of Motion Pictures: Meeting Information, 1951-1963, 1951-1963 (Box 13, Folder 27)
    - The Robert Flahery International Film Seminary, 1955-1965, 1955-1965 (Box 13, Folder 30)
    - Assorted Tutorial Papers for Organizing a Theatre (Box 13, Folder 32)
    - Short Story About a Rat (Box 13, Folder 33)
    - "Notes on W.S.H. Report of Fine Arts Committee," August 3, 1965, August 3, 1965 (Box 13, Folder 64)
    - Undated Calendar with Planned Films (Box 13, Folder 65)
    - "Tormentor Construction for Yoke and Swinging Arm Units," June 1925, June 12, 1925 (Box 13, Folder 71)
    - Articles on "The March of Time," 1935-1959, 1935-1959 (Box 13, Folder 72)
    - Various Documents Concerning Society of Cinema Collectors and Historians, 1954-1957, 1954-1957 (Box 13, Folder 73)
    - "The Prowler," from the Society of Cinema Collectors and Historians, 1955, 1955 (Box 13, Folder 74)
    - "The Cinema Collector," 1955-1969, 1955-1969 (Box 13, Folder 75)
    - Journal of the Society of Cinema Collectors and Historians, 1961, 1961 (Box 13, Folder 77)
    - "Broadway and its Extensions," by Barrett H. Clark (Box 13, Folder 79)
    - "Away from Scenic Realism," by Herbert Philippi (Box 13, Folder 80)
    - "Design in the Theatre," by George P. Crepeau (Box 13, Folder 81)
    - "Make-Up," by Edward D. Ruman (Box 13, Folder 82)
    - "A Policy Standard Re: Adult Education and Community Theatres," Prepared by R.J. Pulling (Box 13, Folder 83)
    - "Producing a Variety Show," by Mary Selvig (Box 13, Folder 84)
    - Department of Speech Exhibit at Drill Hall, 1940, 1940 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Photos of Stainton from January 1947 Alumni News, Accompanied by Technical Photos, January 15, 1947 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Satchel that Stainton Carried Playbills In (Box 14)
    - Statistics Concerning University Film Programs (Box 15, Folder 25)
    - "A Very Short Report on Film Activities at Cornell," by Anthony Caputi, David Grossvogel, Gorden Beck (Box 15, Folder 26)
    - Assorted Documents, Most Concerning Stainton's Career (Box 15, Folder 27)
    - Note Cards Listing Stainton's Various Contributions and Achievements (Box 15, Folder 28)
    - American Council on Education, Film Study Conference, 1964, 1964 (Box 15, Folder 37)
    - Announcement of Second New York Film Festival (Box 15, Folder 38)
- Series X. Ithaca and Upstate New York
  - Official Documents and Notices Concerning Ithaca Torch Club (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Programs and Papers from Various Torch Club Events, 1955-1975, 1955-1975; Also newspaper clipping mentioning result of 1970 Torch Club elections with Stainton as Director. (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Membership Information for Ithaca Torch Club, 1959-1975, 1959-1975 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence Concerning Torch Club, Especially Meeting Reminders, 1959-1981, 1959-1987 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Presentation by Stainton to Ithaca Torch Club on "The History of the Cinema," 1968, April 8, 1968 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - "Revival of Religion in Ithaca" by Rev. William Wisner and "Nations Amenable to God," 1841, 1841 (Box 9, Folder 40)
  - "Early History of Ithaca," by Horace King, 1847, 1847 (Box 9, Folder 41)
  - "Ithaca as it was and Ithaca as itis," by H.C. Goodwin, 1853, 1843 (Box 9, Folder 42)
  - Playbill and Newspaper Articles About 151st Year of Tompkins County, April 1967, April 1967 (Box 9, Folder 43)
  - "The Town Crier and Shopper's Guide," 1967, May 10, 1967 (Box 9, Folder 44)
  - "A Walk Around the Block:" Article by Alison Bishop About Ithaca, 1969, October 3, 1969 (Box 9, Folder 45)
  - Document Explaining the Old courthouse Should Be a Historical Museum, 1970, May 19, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 46)
  - "The Old Courthouse" by Lois O'Connor, May 1970, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 47)
  - Various Articles from the Ithaca Journal, 1970s, 1970s (Box 9, Folder 48)
  - Papers from Historic Ithaca Benefit Auction, March 29, 1973, March 29, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 49)
  - Documents and Newspaper Article Concerning Sale of Frear Estate, 1978-1979, 1978-1979 (Box 9, Folder 50)
  - "The Way They Looked: A Visual History of Dress in Tompkins County" (Box 9, Folder 51)
  - Old Homes in Ithaca (Box 9, Folder 52)
  - "A Guide to Oral History for Schools and Historical Societies" (Box 9, Folder 53)
  - Assorted Newspaper Articles on Past and Present Ithaca (Box 9, Folder 54)
  - Various Newspaper Articles from the Ithaca Journal and the Midweek Examiner (Box 9, Folder 55)
  - Pamphlets and Booklets Concerning Upstate NY/Ithaca History (Box 9, Folder 56)
  - "Ithaca: Past and Present," 1956, 1956 (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - New York State Theatre Conference, 1947-1956, 1947-1956 (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - New York State Community Theatre Conference, October 1947-1960, October 1947-1960 (Box 13, Folder 24)
  - Ithaca Community Players Documents, 1949-1954, 1949-1954 (Box 13, Folder 25)
  - "Community Theatre Bulletin," September 1954/December 1955, September 1954/December 1955 (Box 13, Folder 29)
  - New York State Community Theatre Association Documents (Box 13, Folder 31)
  - "Romantic New York State;" Reading List by Harodl W. Thompson, A.M. Drummond, and Robert E. Gard (Box 13, Folder 66)
  - Dewitt Historical Society
    - Assorted Papers About Dewitt Historical Society and Tompkins County (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - Dewitt Historical Society Meeting Minutes, January-March 1951 (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - Dewitt Historical Society of Tompkins County Bulletin, 1960-1971 (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - Dewitt Historical Society Assorted Newsletters and Pamphlets, 1968-1986, 1968-1986 (Box 9, Folder 25)
    - Correspondence Concerning Dewitt Historical Society, 1969-1985, 1969-1985 (Box 9, Folder 26)
    - Dewitt Historical Society Minutes, 1973-1987, 1973-1987 (Box 9, Folder 27)
    - Dewitt Historical Society of Tompkins Couny Newsletter, 1974-1981, 1974-1981 (Box 9, Folder 28)
    - Meeting Minutes of Dewitt Historical society, 1978-1979, September 14, 1978-July 19, 1979 (Box 9, Folder 29)
    - Dewitt Historical Society Meeting Minutes, 1979-1980, December 1979-1980 (Box 9, Folder 30)
    - Dewitt Historical Society Newsletter, 1982-1987, 1982-1987 (Box 9, Folder 31)
- Series XI. Assorted Newspaper and Magazine Articles
  - Film Articles
    - Assorted News Clippings, 1958-1959, 1958-1959; Some contain information about Ithaca's famous film industry. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Article with Lionel Barrymore About Talkies (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Assorted Magazine Articles Concerning Film, 1965-1970, 1965-1970 (Box 3, Folder 102)
    - Assorted Newspaper Articles on Film and Current Events (Box 4, Folder 55)
    - "The Spirit of the Campus," Film Details, 1932, 1932 (Box 10, Folder 77)
    - "The Shooting Script of the Forum Scene in 'Julius Caesar,'" 1946, April 1946 (Box 10, Folder 78)
    - "Approaches to Film as an Art Form," by Jack C. Ellis, 1955, May 26, 1955 (Box 10, Folder 80)
    - "History of Sound Motion Pictures," Edward W. Kellogg, 1955, Summer 1955 (Box 10, Folder 81)
    - Editorial "Movie Moguls" and Response by Professor Gordon Beck, 1965, October 1963 (Box 10, Folder 85)
    - Article on the Lost Art of Cinema (Box 10, Folder 86)
    - Assorted Articles and Publications on Film (Box 10, Folder 90)
    - Several Papers Arguing "Film vs Theatre" (Box 10, Folder 94)